
//creating an array and passing the number, questions, options amd answers
let MCQS = [

    {
        question: "In questions below, from One to Ten choose the word(s) or phrase which best fills the gap(s) <br><br> Jubril found that thieves had entered his house in his absence. He went to the police to report the... ",
        answer:"break in",
        options:[
         "break out ",
        "break up ",
         "break in",
        "break into",
        ]        
    },


    {
        question:"In adicot leaf, guard cellsdiffer fromother epidermal cells because they",
        answer: "acknuclei",
        options:[
            "have no definite shape",
            "acknuclei",
            "aresmaller",
            "lack vacuole.",
        ]              
    },
    
    {
        question:"Which of the following structures is NOT found in the femaleagamalizard?",
        answer:"Nasal scale",
        options:[
        "Nasal scale",
        "Nuchalcrest.",
        "Gularfold",
        "Eardrum",

        ]
        
    },
    
    {
        question: "Herbs differ from shrubs because they",
        answer:"are onlyperennials.",
        options:[
         "are useful to herbalists",
        "are onlyannuals",
         "are onlyperennials.",
        "donot produce fruits",
        ]        
    },
    {
        question: "Ifan isolatedlivingcellis leftin distilledwater for two hours,itis likelyto",
        answer: "lose some of itswater to the surrounding water",
        options:[
            "lose some of itswater to the surrounding water",
           "loseall ofitswater to the surroundingwater",
         "reproduce bybinaryfission",
       "becomemore turgid.",
        ]      
        
    },

    {
        question: "If an organic compound has its Hydrogen: Oxygen ratio as 2:1, it is likely to be",
        answer:  "an aminoacid.",
        options:[
         "a protein",
         "an aminoacid.",
         "a carbohydrate,",
        "a fat",
        ]
        
        
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following elements are necessary for the formationofchlorophyll ina plant?",
        answer: "Phosphorus and potassium.",
        options:[
        "Calciumandpotassium",
        "Potassiumandsulphur",
        "Calciumandsulphur",
        "Phosphorus and potassium.",
        ]
        
        
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statements is NOT true of mammalianerythrocytes?",
        answer:"They have nuclei at maturity.",
        options:[
            "They have haemoglobin",
            "They have nuclei at maturity.",
             "They have haemoglobin",
            "The cells aremore numerous than leucocytes",
        ]
       
        
    },
    {
        question: "In woody plants, gases and water vapour are transported across the stems by the",
        answer:"medullary fibres",
        options:[
             "medullary fibres",
             "phloem fibres",
             "phloem parenchyma",
            "xylem fibres",
        ]
       
        
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following substances isNOTfound in urine?",
        answer: "Sodium chloride",
        options:[
          "Nitrogenous salts",
         "Water",
         "Calcium chloride",
        "Sodium chloride",
        ]
        
        
    },
    {
        question: "The kidneys of all vertebrates act as osmo regulators. Thismeans that they",
        answer:"Control the volume of blood entering the kidneys",
        options:[
            "keep the composition of the plasma constant",
        "regulate osmoticprocesses",
         "Control the volume of blood entering the kidneys",
         "increase the osmotic pressure of blood.",
        ]
        
        
    },

    {
        question:"Which of the following structures is NOT found in the femaleagamalizard?",
        answer:"Nasal scale",
        options:[
        "Nasal scale",
        "Nuchalcrest.",
        "Gularfold",
        "Eardrum",

        ]
        
    },
    
    {
        question: "Herbs differ from shrubs because they",
        answer:"are onlyperennials.",
        options:[
         "are useful to herbalists",
        "are onlyannuals",
         "are onlyperennials.",
        "donot produce fruits",
        ]        
    },
   
];
